for this project any category for yarn
will work but I used a half a skein of
line brands pad of love in elephant gray
asked for tools a four millimeter hook
scissors stitch markers and a tape
measure there is a written pattern down
below use offer Cote CD DIY for a
discount off any $9.99 plus order watch
the end of the video to learn how to
answer this week's giveaway we're using
4 stitches for this project and they
will be as follows chain slip stitch
single crochet half double crochet and
double crochet this tutorial is for size
small but you can adjust it for your
size and we explain how to in the video
so let's get started getting this top
started we are first going to grab our
category 4 yarn and make a slipknot next
we are going to grab our 4 millimeter
hook and start off by making a chain
that goes from our underarm down to
where we want the bottom of this top to
be keeping in mind that we will have
about an inch for our strap as well so
I'm going to start off by making a chain
of eight and a half inches or 22
centimeters or that comes out to about
forty two chains and mine will be a crop
top but go ahead and make this longer if
you guys want more length to your top
once we have our chain what we're gonna
do from here is block off that last
chain do a chain up of one and then into
that chain that we blocked off or the
second chain from our hook we're going
to go in with a slip stitch so go ahead
and insert yarn over and pull through
everything let's do the next one
together insert it into that next chain
yarn over and pull through everything
and we're going to keep doing this going
all the way down our chain and I know
that we do a lot of slip stitches within
this channel and we get a lot of
questions on how to get the same look
but with a different stitch because some
slip stitches may be a little tighter
than others and if you guys want then
you guys are more than welcome to go
into this row with a single crochet row
and then the rest of this pattern with
back loop single crochets and now that
we made our way all the way down with
our first row and we're going to need to
do an increase from here so from here
we're going to do a chain out of two and
flip our work and into that second chain
that we have from our hook we're going
to go in with a back loop slip stitch so
go ahead and insert your hook into that
back loop
we're gonna yarn over and pull through
that stitch and that counts as our
increase and then from here we're gonna
go all the way down putting one slip
stitch into every back loop going all
the way down and this is basically the
pattern for the rest of this section of
the body portion so we're just going to
keep doing this until this part that we
have right here goes from our side over
to the front of our body and don't mind
if this doesn't go all the way up to our
shoulder or our collarbone whatever the
case may be because we are going to have
a border as well so do back loop slip
stitches down to the end do a chain up
of one and flip and when you work your
way back maintain doing an increase on
this side we're gonna keep doing this
until it's reaches the front of our body
and when we're measuring it up to
ourselves for gonna make sure to stretch
it as if we're wearing it because it's
the stitch that has more give I'll meet
you guys back just after your fruit
loops all right so we are back and we
have just finished up going in with our
underarm portion that we have right here
and I know it looks awfully small but
like I said in the previous clip this
does stretch quite a bit and unstretched
I have a total width of three and a half
inches or eight centimeters or a total
of twenty-one rows if you guys want to
follow my pattern but once when we have
this we are now just going to do a chunk
that goes straight across our chest so
we're not gonna be doing any more
increases we're just gonna do a chain
above one at each end and then just go
all the way back down with back loop
slip stitches we're just gonna keep
going back and forth like that until
this reaches the other side of our chest
and then we're gonna do another decrease
portion just like this so I'll meet you
guys back after we have this entire
section finished up alright so we are
back and we have just finished up going
in with the body portion and from the
first row all the way in to where I
ended I have a total of 59 rows or in
total unstressed I have a total of 8
inches or 20 centimeters and we are now
ready to get started on the other
underarm portion which is pretty much
the same thing that we did on this side
but what decreases instead of increases
we're gonna be decreasing into every
other row since we increased into every
other row on this side and last tip is
that if you guys actually ended on the
bottom you guys do one of two things
either just do back loops of stitches
coming all the way up so that we can all
start on the same side which is
completely fine it won't give you any
extra room or you guys can stay down
there and then work your way up leaving
the last two stitches and then just do
back loop slip stitches into there but
either way I'm going to show you guys
how to do that right now
so when we're ready to get started to do
our back loop slip stitches decreasing
what we're gonna do is depending on what
side run I'm gonna be doing a chain up
of one and flipping my work and I'm
going to insert my hook into that first
available back loop yarn over pull
through and then into that next
available back loop we should have three
loops on our hook from here within the
yarn over and pull through all three
stitches and that is how we decrease
from here we're just gonna work our way
all the way down putting without
splitting the yarn putting one back loop
slip stitch into every stitch that we
have and then when we work our way back
up or your next row depending on what
direction you guys are going we aren't
going to be doing anything into that
next row since we are only going to be
doing decreases into every other row so
we're going to keep doing that until we
end up having the same amount of
stitches that we have along this side
and then the last row that we should
have for this underarm portion should
have the same amount of stitches as we
made for our initial chain so I will
meet you guys back once we have this
entire chunk finished up do a chain up
of one and cut once we have that last
row and I'll show you guys how to do the
back panel alright so we are back with
the entirety of our front panel and I
ended up having a total of 79 rows or
the total width that we have is 11
inches or 29 centimeters unstretched and
we're actually gonna get started on the
back panel the back panel is going to be
very similar to this one but not quite
the same I'm just gonna explain it to
you guys really quickly what we're gonna
do is end up making a chain of the same
amount as the first chain that we made
so mine was a total of 42 chains and
then from here we're going to start
doing our increases going up and then
we're going to go past where we stopped
to go in with the body portion because
the back panel is going to be more of a
racerback
so it's going to come up just a little
bit further so what I'm gonna do is get
started on this portion where I'm gonna
start increasing I'm going to go in with
my total of increasing rows and then
I'll meet you guys back to let you guys
know how many rows I ended up going in
with and then we can move on from there
alright so we are back and we have just
finished up going in with the underarm
portion that we had for the back panel
and as you guys can see it is a smidge
bit taller than my front panel so I
ended up going in with a total of 31
rows for the first portion of our back
piece and then I also had a width of 4
inches or about 10 centimeters
and from here just like how we did the
front we're gonna go straight across
with our back portion but we want our
front and our back piece to come out
with the same amount of rows so what
we're gonna do is take the number of
rows that we have for the front panel
subtract it with the number of rows that
we have for the underarm portion for the
back because we're gonna have the same
amount of rows for the other side and
then whatever number we have we're going
to make that amount of rows so all we're
going to do is do a chain up of one flip
our work and then just put one back loop
slip stitch into every stitch that we
have going back and forth and so we have
fulfilled that amount of rows that we
need and then I'll meet you guys back
just so we can start off doing our other
underarm portion together but it's just
gonna be the same as we did the other
side but I'll meet you guys back anyways
we have just made our way down with the
tiny back portion that we have for our
back piece and from where I started all
the way down to where I ended I have a
total of 49 rows or the width is 6
inches or 15 centimeters and from here
we're just gonna start off our other
underarm portion in the same way that we
started off the front panel by doing
some decreases into every other row so
we're just going to get started with our
decrease of two back loops slip stitches
together into this top corner and then
I'll let you guys do the rest on your
own so since I ended up at the top what
I'm going to be doing is a chain up of
one and flip if you guys ended on the
bottom or if your front panels different
you guys are basically going to be doing
the same thing that you guys have for
your front panels so just adjust from
there but we are gonna do our decrease
together so we're gonna insert our hook
into the first available back loop yarn
over pull through and then into the next
available back loop from here we're
gonna yarn over and pull through all
three loops on our hook and from here
we're just going to go all the way down
putting back loop slip stitches just one
into every stitch to a chain up of one
that's when you get to the end and then
work our way back putting one back loop
slip stitch into every stitch and we're
just going to be decreasing into every
other row until we have the same amount
of rows that we have for this first
underarm portion that we had for the
back double checking and making sure
that we ended up with the same amount of
stitches as chains that we made so I'll
meet you guys back once when all of that
is done we have just finished up going
in with our back panel and the next
thing we're going to have to do is go
into the row of single crochet along the
tops of both pieces that we have I've
already gone in to the tops of my back
panel they're gonna be done the same
exact way so we're just going to do the
front together so all this is is we're
going to start this off by inserting our
hook into this top corner loop inserting
our yarn on
hook and pulling through once we have
that we're just gonna be putting one
single crochet into every side slip
stitch row that we have going all the
way across the top once when you get to
the other end we're going to do a chain
up of one end cut but the only thing
that we're gonna do is once when we get
to this corner we're just going to be
sure to insert our stitch markers just
so we know where our armhole starts and
ends so we're just gonna do the first
few together once we have our hook
inserted we're going to do a chain up of
one and just do the next one together
we're going to be inserting our hook
into this first side slip stitch row and
single crochet and this may be a little
tricky because we don't have any real
loops for us to go into but we're just
gonna have to eyeball and see whichever
one is on top the next one is this
little divot that I have right here
there's my next single crochet this next
side slip stitch row is this raised one
so I'm gonna single crochet into there
we're just gonna keep doing that going
all the way around making sure that we
are inserting our stitch markers into
the correct loops and we're going to do
the same thing to the back panel as well
so we have just made our way all the way
around doing a row of single crochet
along the tops of our front and our back
panel and now I can go in with our side
seam I already did one entire side don't
mind this but what we're going to do is
turn a work to its side and we're going
to be inserting our hook into this
corner loop that we have into the front
panel and this corner loop that we have
into the back panel go ahead and insert
your yarn onto your hook and then pull
through once we have that we're going to
do a chain up of one and into it the
first available stitch we have into the
front panel go ahead and insert your
hook and then into the next available
stitch we have in our back panel go
ahead and insert your hook into there
and then single crochet and we are going
to keep doing this going all the way up
until we hit this last stitch that we
have into this portion and then I'll
meet you guys back so we can get started
on the strap so we have just finished up
seaming up the sides and what we're
going to do next is go straight into
doing the strap the first thing that
we're gonna have to do is insert our
stitch marker and this is for everyone
doesn't matter what size you guys are
doing but we're going to be inserting
our stitch marker into the sixth stitch
that we have away from our hook on both
sides so one in the front and one in the
back and we're doing these few rows so
that our strap doesn't stick straight
out underneath our underarm so what
we're going to do from here is we are
all going to get started on
our back panel first for pattern sake
you're going to flip our work if we need
and remember our back panel is the one
that has the really long underarm
portion right here so what we're all
going to do is start off by doing a
chain out of six once we have our chain
we are going to block off that last
chain do a chain up of one and then into
the first two chains we're going to go
in with two single crochets so just one
single crochet into that first chain
into the second chain go in with another
single crochet into the next two we're
going to be putting one half double into
each of those so there is one half
double and then there's two half double
and then into the last two you guys
guessed it two doubles so one double
into the fifth and then one double into
that six and now we're going to attach
it into the back panel so I'm just gonna
flip my work so it's easier for me to
show you guys how to attach it well all
we're gonna do is count up the next two
stitches making sure we're going into
the back panel and we're going to slip
stitch into that second stitch so we're
going to count up one count up to insert
our hook into that second yarn over and
pull through everything and that is how
we attach our first row we're going to
be doing two more rows of this so a
total of three how we start off the next
row is by going in to the next two
stitches putting one slip stitch into
each flipping our work and then now
we're going to go in with back loop
stitches so into the first two loops
we're going to go in with two back loop
double crochets so there is one back
loop double to back loop double to back
loop half double and then to back loop
singles now that we're at the end we're
going to do a chain up of one flip our
work and then do the same sequence going
down but with back loops so two back
loop singles
to back loop half doubles
and then to back loop doubles
now we should be at our next stitch
marker so we're gonna count up one count
of two stitches why don't you take out
the stitch marker because we don't need
it anymore
yarn over and pull through everything
and now this little triangle section is
all finished off and now that we have
these three rows we're just going to be
going in with rows of back loop half
double crochet it's going all the way up
until we hit this stitch marker remember
we insert those when we were going in
with our single crochet on top of our
panels and then we're going to do more
rows of back loop half doubles that
aren't attached to anything and that is
going to be our strap so we're just
gonna start off the next row with each
other we're going to slip stitch up the
next two stitches flip our work and then
from here we're going to be putting one
back loop half double crochet into every
stitch and when we get to the end of our
back loop half double crochet row we're
going to do a chain up of two flip our
work and then just put one back loop
half double crochet into every stitch
and insert into the base the same way
that we've been doing we're gonna keep
going back and forth just like that
until we hit this corner stitch marker
and then I'll meet you guys back
we've just finished up going all the way
up our back panel for our underarm
portion and from here we're just gonna
go back and forth with back loop half
double crochets just putting one into
every stitch so just to start off this
section with you guys we're going to do
a chain up of two and then put one back
loop half double crochet into every
stitch that we have and we're going to
keep going until we get a length that
can go up and over our shoulder that
will connect to the front panel now I
have already measured my now and I'm
gonna have a total of nine inches or 23
centimeters going all the way up from
our back panel to the stitch that we
have right here and the only thing that
I have to mention for you guys before I
let you go is to make sure that when
we're going in with our back loop half
double crochets we're going to end along
the inside and by the inside I mean the
side that is closest to the body so that
we don't need to cut and tie and
reattach into this corner so that we can
slip stitch into this corner I'll meet
you guys back in the next clip just to
let you guys know what I mean but other
than that go ahead and keep going with
your back loop half double crochets we
are now back with the entirety of our
strap and like I said in the previous
clip I did end along the inside which is
the corner that is closed
to the body portion and I ended up
having a total of 39 rows and that is
including these rows that we first
started off with as well but once when
we get here we're actually going to slip
stitch into this corner stitch marker
that we have and then we're going to do
our back loop half double crochets going
all the way down until we hit this
stitch marker and then we're going to do
the same singles two half doubles two
doubles that we did when we started off
this entire strap so what we're gonna do
from here is slip stitch it into that
stitch that our stitch marker is in
we're gonna yarn over and pull through
and now that we're into that corner
stitch we're gonna be slip stitching
into the next two to work our way up to
the next row so into that next stitch
that we have slip stitch one slip stitch
to flip our work and then just go
straight in with our back loop half
double crochets until we hit our next
stitch marker so we are back and I have
just made my way all the way down to
where my stitch marker was I did take
mine out because I don't need it anymore
but from here we're just going to do the
same thing that we did when we started
off this entire section and this part is
all gonna vary depending on whether you
guys end at the top or at the bottom
like me but it's all pretty much gonna
be the same just as an example if you
guys ended at the top you guys are gonna
do a chain up of one and then do two
back loop singles to back loop half
doubles two back loop doubles and then
basically just repeat the same thing
that we did on this other side we're
just starting off a little differently
but just to start off this section with
you guys I'm going to slip stitch into
the next two stitches so there's one and
there's two from here we're going to
flip our work and then I'm gonna start
off by doing two back loop double
crochets two back loop half double
crochets
and then to back loop singles and we're
going to repeat so do a chain up of one
and flip and then do two back loop
singles to back up half doubles to back
loop doubles and then another row of two
back loop doubles to back the path
doubles to back loops singles and then
I'll meet you guys back so that we can
seen this up so we've just made our way
down we don't have any more loops left
to go into when it comes to this
underarm portion and now we're just
going to seam everything up together we
are first going to want to make sure
that our seams are all facing the same
direction and then we're gonna insert
our hook into the corner loop that we
have into the front panel and then also
into the corner loop that we have in the
back panel mine just so happens to be my
loop we're going to pull through from
here we're going to do a chain up of one
to secure and then insert your hook into
that first available stitch that we have
into the front panel next available
stitch that we have into the back panel
and single crochet and keep doing that
going all the way down until we don't
have any more stitches left once when we
don't do a chain up of one and cut and
then do this entire sequence here on the
other side and then I'll meet you guys
back so we can do just one more thing
now that we have both of our straps done
the last thing we're going to do is just
go in with this top border that we're
gonna have only going into the front so
what we're gonna do is first turn our
work to the side and then we're going to
take a look at these two rows that we
have that is coming straight out of this
corner so there's one row and then
there's two rows right here we're gonna
be inserting our hook and then we're
going to insert our hook into the loop
that we have in between that second and
third row and from here we're going to
work along the length so just to start
this off you're gonna insert our yarn
onto our hook pull through and do a
chain up of two that counts as a half
double crochet and we have these two
rows that we have that's right next to
the front single crochet row that we
just did so we're gonna be putting two
single crochets into each of these half
side double crochet rows so we're going
to prepare for a half double crochet go
into this first side half double with
one half double and then going into that
same loop there is two half doubles
they're gonna do the same thing into the
next side half double crochet row it
should be the one that's right next to
this work
so we're going to prepare into that next
side half double there is one and then
into that same one here is two and once
when we have that we are going to be
slip stitching into the second stitch
that we have going into the single
crochet section so we're going to count
one count to go into that second one
with a slip stitch and this is going to
be pretty much the same way that we went
in with our strap let's just do the next
one together and let you guys do the
rest on your own so we're going to slip
stitch up the next two stitches there's
one there's two and flip our work and
from here just put one back loop half
double crochet into each stitch that we
have and then once we make our way down
to the end do a chain up of two flip our
work and then do the same thing going
all the way down and we're going to be
repeating these rows going all the way
down until we don't have any more
stitches left to go into then I'll show
you guys how to connect it into here
we've just made our way all the way down
going in with our front order and all
we're gonna do from here is just seam up
these two sides that we have we're just
going to want to make sure that all of
our seams our face the same directions
so let me just slip my wrong side out
really quick so now that my work is
slipped wrong side out what we're gonna
do from here is just seen this up but we
are gonna want to make sure that we are
inserting our hook first into the same
loop that we inserted our hook into when
we started this off so from here from
this corner we're gonna count up one two
of the half double crochet rows and then
in between the second and the third
there's gonna be a loop right in between
there go ahead and insert your hook into
there and then also into this loop that
we have for this row right here and from
here we're going to pull through do a
chain up of one to secure and then we're
just gonna go in putting two single
crochets into each of the side half
doubles so once into that first stitch
we're gonna insert into that side half
double once into that next stitch single
crochet and then the next single is
going to go into that same side half
double put into the next stitch into the
back in single crochet and I just have
one more to go so let's do this together
go ahead and insert your hook into that
next side half double into that next
stitch we have into the back single into
that same
side half-double insert our hook into
that next stitch into the back and
single and from here go ahead and do a
chain up of line and cut and now that we
have attached that we are actually all
done the last thing we have to do is
just weave in all of our ends our ends
are woven in and this is our finished
tank this is an easy piece to make and
would match pretty much everything in
your closet so go ahead and make this
cropped or as a long tank top and you're
ready to go there's a written pattern
down below use offer Cote CD DIY for a
discount off any $9.99 plus order enter
this week's pattern giveaway by telling
us your favorite summer memory good luck
to everyone who enters also if you like
this video give it a big thumbs up cuz
believe it or not it actually helps and
be sure to share us on Twitter Pinterest
Instagram and Facebook links down below
link to our Etsy pages down there too if
you want to buy this piece or any other
piece on the channel and be sure to
favour the shop so you don't miss out on
new patterns and exclusive deals thank
you guys so so much for watching and
I'll see you all in the next one